RUBEN A. SANCHEZ

EDUCATION		
2015 2015	B.A. Linguistics B.S. Cognitive Science	University of California, Santa Cruz University of California, Santa Cruz
PUBLICATION		
2019	Zyzik, E.C., & Sanchez, R.A. (2019). Beyond accuracy: Heritage speakers' performance on two kinds of acceptability judgment tasks. <i>Applied Psycholinguistics</i> , 40(3), 645-671. http://doi.org/10.1017/S0142716418000760	
AWARDS		
2021 2015 2012 to 2014	Macquarie Group Scholarship UCSC Scholarship Undergraduate Dean's Award	
RESEARCH EXPERIENCE		
2017 to 2018	Data Analyst - Bilingualism Research Lab Responsible for conducting data pre-processing, codin analysis, inferential analysis, data visualizations, and	
2016	Annotator - Natural Language & Dialogue Systems Annotated social media content for computational monarrative summarizations.	University of California, Santa Cruz odeling via language entrainment and
2013 to 2014	Research Assistant - Cognitive Science Department Coded acoustic data with Praat and video data with study.	University of California, Santa Cruz After Effects for a linguistic phonetic
2012	Research Assistant - Linguistics Department Developed, implemented, and completed a phonologic stimuli, scheduled and ran participants, as well as ana	
TEACHING EXPERIENCE		
2020	Academic Success Mentor Served as advisor for student at risk of loosing residency due to failed coursework. - Guided student through studying best practices. - Developed a strategy plan for completing assignments. - Advised on stress coping mechanisms and directed to resources. - Student successfully completed the quarter and graduated.	

2018 to 2019

Private Tutor

Tutored college students in mathematics.

LEADERSHIP & SERVICE

2018 to 2019 Volunteer - English composition tutor for international students.

2013 to 2014 Community Liaison Officer - Undergraduate Research Science Association

2012 Founder & President - Spanish Languages & Spanish Cultures Club

2011 Co-founder - Volunteer based community outreach writing tutoring service.

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Expertise Cognitive research, neurolinguistics, phonetic psycholinguistics, data visualization,

web development, illustration, and 2D animation.

Research Interested in investigating the neural circuitry responsible for the assignment of semantic

Interests coding onto phonetic units perceived as linguistically relevant.

Also interested in multimodal communicative strategies for human computer interaction.

Programming Python, R, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, GIT, CLI, bash, LATEX, markdown

Research E-Prime, SuperLab, Praat, Audacity, ELAN, SPSS, Mendeley, Zotero

Design Photoshop, Illustrator, After Effects, Figma, Invision, Blender

Leadership Project Management, Team Building, Issue Resolution

Languages English, Italian, Spanish, learning Japanese

CURRENT PROJECTS

2021 Web Based Interactive 3D Brain Model

Teaching myself advanced 3D modeling methods for developing an interactive model of the human brain which displays areas currently known to be pertinent to the perception and production of sounds relevant to language.

- Completed design of graphical user interface.
- Completed engineering of information architecture.
- Completed development of shell infrastructure.
- Conducting formal literature review for content incorporation.

2 of 2 October 2021